Lesson 18 Porpoises
海豚
First listen and then answer the following question.
听录音,然后回答以下问题.
porpoise: n.  海豚
What would you say is the main characteristic of porpoises?
你认为海豚的主要特征是什么?
mariner: n.  水手
There has long been a superstition among mariners
长期以来,海员中流传着一种迷信说法,
porpoise: n.  海豚
that porpoises will save drowning men by pushing them to the surface,
认为海豚会把快要淹死的人托到水面,救人性命;
shark: n.  鲨鱼, formation: n.  队形
or protect them from sharks by surrounding them in defensive formation.
或在人们周围列队保护,使他们免遭鲨鱼伤害.
Marine Studio biologists have pointed out that,
海洋摄影室的生物学家指出,
however intelligent they may be,
无论海豚多么聪明,
dolphin: n.  海豚科动物
it is probably a mistake to credit dolphins with any motive of lifesaving.
认为它们有救人的动机可能是错误的.
On the occasions when they have pushed to shore an unconscious human being
当它们偶尔把一个失去知觉的人推到岸边时,
they have much more likely done it out of curiosity or for sport,
更大的可能是出于好奇或游戏,
as in riding the bow waves of a ship.
就像它们追逐被船首犁开的浪花一样.
porpoise: n.  海豚
In 1928 some porpoises were photographed,
1928年,有人拍摄到了海豚，
beaver: n.  海狸
working like beavers to push ashore a waterlogged mattress.
像海狸一样把浸透水的床垫推上岸的情景.
shark: n.  鲨鱼
If,as has been reported,they have protected humans from sharks,
正如报道中所说,如果海豚保护人不受鲨鱼侵害,
it may have been because curiosity attracted them
那它们可能是出于好奇:
shark: n.  鲨鱼, scent: n.  香味
and because the scent of a possible meal attracted the sharks.
而鲨鱼可能是闻到了可以美食一顿的香味.
shark: n.  鲨鱼
Porpoises and sharks are natural enemies.
海豚和鲨鱼是天然仇敌,
ensue: v.  接着发生
It is possible that upon such an occasion a battle ensued,
双方可能随之发生搏斗,
shark: n.  鲨鱼
with the sharks being driven away or killed.
搏斗结果是海豚赶走或咬死鲨鱼.
Whether it be bird, fish or beast,
不管是鸟,是鱼,还是野兽,
porpoise: n.  海豚, intrigue: v.  引起兴趣
the porpoise is intrigued with anything that is alive,
海豚对凡是活动的东西都感兴趣,
They are constantly after the turtles,
它们经常追逐海龟,
who peacefully submit to all sorts of indignities.
海龟则温顺地忍受着各种侮辱.
snout: n.  口鼻部
One young calf especi- ally enjoyed raising a turtle to the surface with his snout,
一只小海豚特别喜欢用鼻子把海龟推到水面,
aquaplane: n.  驾浪滑水板
and then shoving him across the tank like an aquaplane.
然后像滑水板一样把海龟从水池的这一边推到那一边.
porpoise: n.  海豚
Almost any day a young porpoises may be seen trying to turn a 300- pound sea turtle over,
几乎每天都可以看到一只小海豚试图地把一只300磅重的海龟翻过来,
snout: n.  口鼻部
by sticking his snout under the edge of his shell and pushing up for dear life.
它把鼻子顶入海龟的硬壳下面,拼命地顶.
porpoise: n.  海豚
This is not easy,and may require two porpoises working together.
这并非易事,可能需要两只海豚合伙干才行.
oceanarium: n.  水族馆
In another game,as the turtle swims across the oceanarium,
在另一场游戏中,当海龟游过水族馆时,
porpoise: n.  海豚, swoop: v.  猛扑, belly: n.  腹部, butt: v.  碰撞
the first porpoise swoops down from above and butts his shell with his belly.
第一只海豚从上方猛扑下去,用腹部撞击龟壳.
This knocks the turtle down several feet.
这一下子把海龟撞下去好几英尺.
equilibrium: n.  平衡
He no sooner recovers his equilibrium,
海龟刚恢复平衡,
porpoise: n.  海豚, crack: n.  重击
than the next porpoises comes along and hits him another crack.
第二只海豚又冲过来猛击一下.
butt: v.  碰撞
Eventually the turtle has been butted all the way down to the floor of the tank.
这只海龟最终被撞到池底.
He is now satisfied merely to try to stand up,
此时的海龟,只要能站起来就满足了,
porpoise: n.  海豚
but as soon as he does so a porpoise knocks him flat.
但它刚站起来,就被一只海豚击倒.
The turtle at last gives up by pulling his feet under his shell
海龟终于屈服了,将4条腿缩进壳内.
and the game is over.
游戏到此结束.